{"tossups": [{"question": "This man's sting operations resulted in over four thousand arrests and fifteen suicides, including those of Ida Craddock and Madame Restell. This man had George Bernard Shaw's <em>Man and Superman</em> removed from the New York Public Library and targeted birth control providers. In collaboration with the New York state legislature, this man founded the Society for the Suppression of Vice. For ten points, name this Postal Inspector whose namesake federal laws prohibited the mailing of material which was considered \"obscene.\"", "answer": "Anthony <b><u>Comstock</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "William II [[the second]] de La Marck led a raiding group in this war which attacked Brielle under Willem Bloys van Treslong. That group in this war used the slogan \"Rather Turkish than Pope\" and were known as the <em>Watergeuzen</em> [[VAH-tuh-guhr-zen]]. The Twelve Years Truce and the Synod of Dort divided this war into two sections. The Council of Troubles, or the Blood Council, was created in this war by the Duke of Alba. Ghent was pacified, and Antwerp was sacked in this war. Philip II tried to crush a revolt in the low countries in, for ten points, what 1568 to 1648 war?", "answer": "<b><u>Dutch Revolt</u></b> (accept <b><u>Eighty Years'</u></b> War; accept War of <b><u>Dutch Independence</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In this case, Potter Stewart compared the central practice to \u201cbeing struck by lightning\u201d and claimed that said practice was experienced by \u201ca capriciously selected random handful.\u201d The death of William Micke occurred during the central crime in this case in which an \u201cevolving standard of decency\u201d was invoked. The position affirmed in this case was effectively abandoned with a decision four years later involving Troy Leon Gregg. Dealing with a burglar who killed his victim, this 1972 case tested the Eighth Amendment. For ten points, name this Supreme Court case dealing with the death penalty.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Furman</u></b> v. Georgia</em> (or <em>William Henry</em> <em><b><u>Furman</u></b> v. State of Georgia</em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Works by this man subtitled <em>The Good Soldier</em> and <em>His Rise and Fall</em> were among the biographies of the leaders of his native country. A work by Henry Timrod set at Magnolia Cemetery had the same theme as this man\u2019s best known work, which begins by noting how \u201cThe headstones yield their names to the element.\u201d Malvern Hill and Bull Run are mentioned in that work by this man which repeats \u201cStonewall, Stonewall.\u201d For ten points, name this Southern U.S. poet of \u201cOde to the Confederate Dead.\u201d", "answer": "Allen <b><u>Tate</u></b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {"question": "An illegitimate member of this family may be shown in <em>Young Girl in Profile</em>. Gerolamo Olgiati and Giovanni Lampugnani killed a duke from this family after Christmas. Francesco Piccinino was beaten at Montolmo by a member of this family, which commissioned <em>The Last Supper</em>. \"Il Moro\" was from this family, who fought Louis XII in the Italian Wars, making weapons from the bronze intended for a Leonardo da Vinci statue to win at Fornovo. After Filippo Visconti died, the Ambrosian Republic was created, followed by, for ten points, what family's rule?", "answer": "<b><u>Sforza</u></b>s (accept Bianca <b><u>Sforza</u></b>; accept Galeazzo Maria <b><u>Sforza</u></b>; accept Ludovico <b><u>Sforza</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A woman known as the \u201cpythoness\u201d of this state, Mary Lease, advised its farmers to \u201craise less corn and more hell.\u201d An editorial written by a native of this state called on politicians to \u201cLegislate the thriftless man into ease\u201d and was used by McKinley supporters to disparage his opponent during the 1896 election. William Allen White wrote the aforementioned editorial for the <em>Emporia Gazette</em> which asked <em>What\u2019s the Matter with</em> [this state]. For ten points, name this Midwestern state through which a railroad named for Santa Fe and two of this state's cities passed.", "answer": "<b><u>Kansas</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In March 2021, this man was arrested in Boise for failing to wear a mask in court at his trial on misdemeanor charges. In July 2020, this man stated, \"You must have a problem in your mind if you think that somehow the Black Lives Matter is more dangerous than the police.\" This man participated in a standoff in Nevada over the question of his father's unpaid grazing fees, leading to the death of LaVoy Finicum. For ten points, name this anti-government militant who led a group of far-right extremists in occupying Malheur National Wildlife Refuge in 2016.", "answer": "Ammon <b><u>Bundy</u></b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This man founded the predecessor to the telecommunications company Intouch Holdings. A movement against this man, who also holds Montenegrin citizenship, accused him of corruption and abuse of power and is known as the Yellow Shirts. This man was overthrown in a 2006 coup and replaced as leader by Sonthi Boonyaratglin [[SOHN-TEE BOON-JAH-RAHT-GLEEN]]. This leader cracked down on Muslim separatists in provinces including Pattani and Narathiwat [[NAH-RAH-TEE-WAHT]]. For ten points, name this founder of the Thai Rak Thai Party and former prime minister of Thailand, the older brother of Yingluck.", "answer": "<b><u>T</u></b>haksin <b><u>Shinawatra</u></b> [[CHEE-NAH-WAHT]] (be very lenient on pronunciation)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "This person headed the John Steinbeck Committee and served as an alternate delegate to the U.N. under Harry Truman. While playing Hash-a-Motep in the movie <em>She</em>, this person popularized the phrase \"She who must be obeyed.\" Against the advice of William Malone, this woman ran in an election in which Sheridan Downey and Manchester Boddy opposed her. This woman, whom Murray Chotiner referred to as the \"Pin Lady,\" coined the term \"Tricky Dick\" for her victorious opponent Richard Nixon. For ten points, name this actress and politician.", "answer": "Helen Gahagan <b><u>Douglas</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In one work by this thinker a figure known as Genius accompanies a drunken man who attempts to use his money chest\u2019s key to unlock the gates of heaven. A request from the religious wife of a soldier for a work that would mend her husband\u2019s conduct inspired a manual written by this man which was translated by William Tyndale. This author of <em>Julius</em> <em>Exclusus</em> and proponent of the <em>via media</em>, or \"middle way,\" satirized superstitions common in Europe in a 1511 work. For ten points, name this \u201cPrince of Humanists\u201d who wrote <em>In</em> <em>Praise of Folly</em>.", "answer": "<b><u>Erasmus</u></b> of Rotterdam (accept Desiderius <b><u>Erasmus</u></b> [Roterodamus])", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "The leader of this political faction was the last individual who, after being confirmed, refused a seat on the Supreme Court. That leader of this faction had served as Thaddeus Stevens's bodyguard in the House. The appointment of William Robertson to a port collector position in New York earned the ire of this faction. Roscoe Conkling was a member of this faction which was opposed to the Half-Breeds. The assassin Charles Guiteau was a supporter of, for ten points, what Republican Party faction which favored the spoils system?", "answer": "<b><u>Stalwart</u></b>s", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Following this conflict, two brothers who were leading members of a liberal faction during it purchased the H\u00f4tel Lambert. This event was put down by Ivan Paskevitch, and the Organic Statute replaced an earlier 1815 constitution in the aftermath of this event. Mass participation of non-commissioned youths inspired this event to be called the \u201cCadet Revolution.\u201d This event inspired a native composer to create the \u201cRevolutionary \u00c9tude.\u201d Resulting in Nicholas I cracking down on the central country, for ten points, what was this 1830-1831 revolution in Poland?", "answer": "<b><u>November</u></b> Uprising (accept synonyms for \"Uprising\" such as \"Rebellion\" or \"Revolution\"; accept <b><u>Cadet</u></b> Revolution before mentioned; accept <b><u>Poland-Russian</u></b> War of 1830-31 before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "William Kendall spent nearly 60 years working for this company, one of whose founders was shot and killed by Harry Thaw. This company was hired to work on the site of the Washington Arsenal to create a building that would host the Army War College. This company, which designed Roosevelt Hall, was better known for a project created in the Beaux Art style whose terminals provided direct rail access to New York City. Penn Station was designed by, for ten points, what architectural firm named for its three founders?", "answer": "<b><u>McKim, Mead & White</u></b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {}, {"question": "On Bloody Island, this man killed Charles Lucas in a rematch of a duel. This man\u2019s daughter, Jessie, wrote a book titled <em>A Year of American Travel</em> which chronicled the governorship of the territory of Arizona by her husband, John C. Fr\u00e9mont. The Specie Circular was inspired by this man\u2019s calls for federal land requiring payments exclusively in hard currency, a proposal which inspired this man's nickname, \u201cOld Bullion.\u201d For ten points, name this Missourian who promoted westward expansion, the first man to be elected to the U.S. Senate five times.", "answer": "Thomas Hart <b><u>Benton</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "John Butler Walden headed this country's army during a period in which the Suicide Battalion rebelled at the Battle of Masaka. This country won at the Gayaza Hills and fought a combined force of Libyans and the PLO in Operation Dada Idi. This country headed the Moshi Conference after a war it won in Kagera. Yusuf Gowon and Idi Amin were defeated by this country, which was led by a Chama Cha Mapiduzi party leader who created Ujamaa. For ten points, in 1965, Julius Nyerere [[nai-eh-REH-reh]] was elected the first president of what African nation?", "answer": "United Republic of <b><u>Tanzania</u></b> (accept Jamhuri ya Muungano wa <b><u>Tanzania</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This woman stands on a gang plank as she is received by a figure adorned in a blue mantle patterned with the fleur de lis in a depiction of a \u201cDisembarkation.\u201d <em>The Education of</em> <em>the Princess</em> and <em>The Coronation in St. Denis</em> are part of a series of 24 paintings focusing on this figure. This queen is shown ascending to the regency in a work sometimes titled <em>The</em> <em>Apotheosis of Henry IV</em>. For ten points, name this French queen from a Florentine banking family, the subject of a series by Peter Paul Rubens.", "answer": "<b><u>Marie</u></b> de' <b><u>Medici</u> </b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This man criticized globalization and the World Bank in <em>The Eyes of the Heart</em>. Before leading his country, this man served as a liberation theology preacher at the Saint-Jean Bosco Church. This man broke off from the FNCD to found the Struggling Peoples\u2019 Organization, and Raoul C\u00e9dras deposed this man in a military coup which prompted the launch of Operation Uphold Democracy. This man spent three years in exile in Canada after denouncing the Duvaliers. Serving four separate terms from 1991 to 2004, for ten points, who is this president of the Republic of Haiti?", "answer": "Jean-Bertrande <b><u>Aristide</u> </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s play <em>Transistor Radio</em> was successfully adapted to the television screen as <em>Basi and Company</em>. The life of an initially idealistic soldier from the village of Dukana named Mene is the subject of a novel by this author written in \u201crotten English.\u201d This man led a movement of the Ogoni people during a campaign protesting extraction of one good that led to the degradation of his homeland. That campaign led by this man protested the oil extraction of Royal Dutch Shell. For ten points, name this activist and author who was executed in 1995 in Nigeria.", "answer": "Kenule Beeson \"Ken\" <b><u>Saro-Wiwa</u> </b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "For her rescue efforts, Australian playwright Millicent Armstrong was given this award. Despite being wounded in the leg, a 25-mile flight was completed by one recipient of this award who helped save nearly 200 American soldiers. The TOE variant of this award was given to recipients in such conflicts as the First Indochina War. A passenger pigeon named Cher Ami [[shehr-ah-MEE]] received one of these awards, another of which was given to a Jesuit priest wounded at Verdun. For ten points, name this French military award whose name means \u201cCross of War.\"", "answer": "<b><u>Croix de Guerre</u></b> [[KWAH-de-GEHR]] (accept <b><u>Cross of War</u></b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "During this event, acts of arson followed a peaceful meeting on Blue Island. The leader of this event ran with Emil Seidel during one of five presidential elections in which he was a third-party candidate. Richard Olney faced this event, one side of which was represented by Clarence Darrow in a subsequent court case. Obstruction of mail delivery was ultimately the reason an injunction was given to Grover Cleveland to end this 1894 event. For ten points, Eugene Debs organized what strike against a company that employed many rail porters?", "answer": "<b><u>Pullman</u></b> Strike", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>In order to excavate this object in 1996, Mike Daniel pieced together research</u></b> <b><u>collected by Intersal Incorporated. Ren\u00e9 Montaudin [[mohn-taw-DAHN]] used this</u></b> <b><u>vessel as a slave ship after being handed it by another Frenchman. Stede Bonnet</u></b> <b><u>ceded control of this vessel to a man who (+)</u> ran it aground at Topsail Inlet. That man had served in the War of the Spanish Succession, which (*) </b>inspired this vessel's best known name. A governor of North Carolina pardoned the owner of this ship whose real name was Edward Teach. For ten points, name this ship used by Blackbeard.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Queen Anne\u2019s Revenge</u></b></em> (accept <em>La</em> <em><b><u>Concord</u></b>e</em>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man wrote an article titled \"They Have Stolen Too Much From Us\" and</u></b> <b><u>formed the African Agricultural Union. Ernest Boka was accused of trying to kill this</u></b> <b><u>man, whose government recovered from debt thanks in part to Alassane Ouattara</u></b> <b><u>[[oo-wah-TAH-rah]]. The UNESCO (*)</u> Peace Prize is named for this man, whose policies were renamed by Fran\u00e7ois-Xavier Verschave [[vehr-SHAHV]] into </b><em><b>Fran\u00e7afrique</b></em><b> [[frans-ah-FREEK]]. This man moved his capital from (*) </b>Abidjan and built the world's largest church in Yamoussoukro. For ten points, name this first president of Ivory Coast.", "answer": "F\u00e9lix <b><u>Houphou\u00ebt</u></b>-Boigny (accept Papa <b><u>Houphou\u00ebt</u></b>; accept Le <b><u>Vieux</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>Though not among the twelve places described by this term, Brest Fortress</u></b> <b><u>was given a similar designation. The first known official use of this term occurred as</u></b> <b><u>part of Special Order #20, which called for the firing of salutes at its central locations.</u></b> <b><u>The Gold Star medal, Order of (*)</u> Lenin, and the </b><em><b>Gramota</b></em><b> are bestowed upon locations of this type, which include Odessa, (*) </b>Sevastopol, and Leningrad. For ten points, name this honorary title given to twelve Soviet cities to honor their efforts during World War Two.", "answer": "<b><u>Hero City</u></b> (accept word forms; accept <b><u>gorod-geroy</u></b>; accept <b><u>misto-heroy</u></b>; accept <b><u>horad-heroy</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>A satirical take on one of this man\u2019s most iconic works depicts Honest Gil</u></b> <b><u>Fulbright wearing a badge with a dollar sign and holding a bundle of cash. A piece by</u></b> <b><u>this man was created to commemorate the 25th anniversary of the Purple Rain</u></b> <b><u>protests. In addition to the (+)</u> Nelson Mandela Mural, this man created a work that originally featured the word \u201cprogress\u201d and depicts its central, suited figure in (*) </b>red, white, and blue. For ten points, name this artist who, in 2008, created the HOPE poster widely used by the Obama campaign.", "answer": "Shepard <b><u>Fairey</u></b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>A National Security Act in this country that gave broad powers to search and</u></b> <b><u>seize property was instituted by Forbes Burnham. A figure considered the father of</u></b> <b><u>this nation was Cheddi Jagan, who was of Indian descent. In the nineteenth century</u></b> <b><u>the (+)</u> Dutch ceded the provinces of Demerara and Essequibo [[eh-seh-KEE-boh]] in this modern-day country to (*) </b>Britain whose colonial legacy is seen in this country\u2019s use of English as an official language. Found between Venezuela and Suriname, for ten points, what is this South American country officially named a \"co-operative republic\"?", "answer": "Co\u2011operative Republic of <b><u>Guyana</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This story may have been copied from a similar one by Giorgio Vasari about</u></b> <b><u>how Filippo Brunelleschi [[broo-neh-LESS-kee]] was chosen to design the Florence</u></b> <b><u>Cathedral\u2019s dome. Often set during a party of Spanish nobles, this story involved a</u></b> <b><u>question \u201cwondered at\u2026as an (+)</u> impossibility\u201d which was answered by the flattening of a portion of the central object to (*) </b>make it stand. Often conflated with seemingly obvious solutions to tough problems, for ten points, what is this story involving an explorer from Genoa and a certain ovoid object?", "answer": "The <b><u>Egg</u></b> of <b><u>Columbus</u></b> (accept similar or descriptive answers including Christopher <b><u>Columbus</u></b> flattening the end of an <b><u>egg</u></b> to make it stand; accept Cristoforo <b><u>Colombo</u></b> in place of Christopher <b><u>Columbus</u></b>; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man came under fire after a joint venture between his organization and</u></b> <b><u>Danone [[dah-NOHN]] was accused of making yogurt with illegally low levels of fat.</u></b> <b><u>Mary Robinson founded a group called the \u201cFriends of\u201d this man\u2019s best known</u></b> <b><u>organization. The Citizens\u2019 Power, or (+)</u> Nagorik Shakti party, was founded by this man, whose main organization was made up of many solidarity groups. Sheikh Hasina is an opponent of this man, whose \u201cLow-Cost Housing Program\u201d grew out of his work at the University of (*) </b>Chittagong. For ten points, name this Bangladeshi founder of Grameen Bank.", "answer": "Muhammad <b><u>Yunus</u></b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b><u>Winston Churchill once said that this politician \"always played the game, and</u></b> <b><u>he always lost it.\" After a vote against his party's continuation of a coalition, this man</u></b> <b><u>resigned as party leader following the Carleton Club meeting. This man helped</u></b> <b><u>negotiate an agreement that aimed to (+)</u> pacify relations between France and Germany, resulting in his reception of a Nobel Peace Prize. The aforementioned (*) </b>Locarno Pact was negotiated by, for ten points, what British statesman, who was the half-brother of prime minister Neville?", "answer": "Joseph <b><u>A</u></b>usten <b><u>Chamberlain</u></b> (prompt on \u201cChamberlain\u201d; do not accept or prompt on \u201cJoseph Chamberlain\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man signed a border agreement with Mexico in 1828 which came to be</u></b> <b><u>known as the Treaty of Limits. Jos\u00e9 Miguel Carrera received this man as a special</u></b> <b><u>agent to Argentina, and this man served in a similar capacity in Chile. The</u></b> <b><u>predecessor to the (+)</u> Smithsonian Institution was co-founded by this man, who in 1822 was appointed the first U.S. minister to Mexico. This man's passion for botany led him to send samples of a plant he saw in (*) </b>Taxco de Alarc\u00f3n to the U.S. for further study. For ten points, identify this man who names a type of plant with red and green foliage.", "answer": "Joel Roberts <b><u>Poinsett</u></b> (anti-prompt on \"Poinsettia\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>After an attempt to get one participant at this event off stage, that participant</u></b> <b><u>replied, \"You push me again...and I\u2019ll deck you right in front of this whole audience.\u201d</u></b> <b><u>Thurston Morton headed this event from which the journalist Belva Davis was forced</u></b> <b><u>to flee. One individual in this event told the audience, (+)</u> \u201cLet me remind you also that moderation in the pursuit of justice is no virtue.\" Supporters of Nelson (*) </b>Rockefeller clashed with those of a man who wrote the book <em>Conscience of a Conservative</em>.  For ten points, name this raucous meeting at which Barry Goldwater was nominated.", "answer": "<b><u>1964 Republican National Convention</u></b> (accept <b><u>RNC</u></b> in place of <b><u>Republican</u></b> <b><u>National Convention</u></b>; prompt on partial answer)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>After Benjamin Franklin, this man was the first American who did not serve as</u></b> <b><u>president to appear on a U.S. postage stamp. John Henry Manny\u2019s legal defense team</u></b> <b><u>against infringement on Cyrus McCormick\u2019s patents prominently included this man,</u></b> <b><u>who was preceded in his highest post by Simon (+)</u> Cameron. This man ordered the lockdown of Washington, D.C. in the aftermath of Abraham Lincoln\u2019s assassination, and this man\u2019s (*) </b>removal from office tested the Tenure of Office Act. For ten points, name this Secretary of War whose removal led to the impeachment of Andrew Johnson.", "answer": "Edwin <b><u>Stanton</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}